YURII **SACHOK**

Kyiv Ukraine · 1 860 348 3211 sachokdev@gmail.com

I am a senior front-end developer with 8+ years of experience. I have worked in several IT companies such as Suitsupply, Liberty, and Intuit. During this period, I have built so many successful projects such as blockchain gaming sites, eshop sites and Saas apps. Seeking to further improve React, Vue.JS, Svelte and Node skills as the future front-end developer at incoming works.

SKILLS

- Languages: C/C++, Java, Javascript, Python, Solidity, Rust
- Front-end: HTML, CSS, React, ReactNative, Vue, Angular, Ajax, jQuery, Svelte, Solidjs, RESTful API, GraphQL, Gatsby.js, Redux, Typescript, Material UI, ES6, Webpack, bable
- Backend: PHP, Node, Postman, Django, Laravel
- Service: AWS(Amplify, Cognito, Lambda, ECS, EC2/S3), Nginx, Heroku, Netlify, Vercel, Plesk,
 Digital Ocean
- Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Firebase

EXPERIENCE

08/2021 - 05/2023

SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER, INTUIT(US)

- Developed Open CMS components.
- Developed various reusable Svelte components.
- Build and deploy smart contract and nft tokens.
- Created Svelte front end for contacting with smart contract using ether.js and web3.js
- Worked closely with the design team to improve website consistency and style guide.
- Collaborating with other cross-functional teams to ensure high-performance of applications
- Technologies: Git, OpenCms, JSON API, XML, Apache Jackrabbit, Adobe Experience Manager, JavaScript, Sass, CSS3, HTML5, Svelte, Blockchain, Solidity, Netlify, AWS Lambda

09/2019 - 07/2021

SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER, GOREHA(REMOTE)

- Led the front-end development of a multi-lingual digital rehabilitation platform.
- Used Angular 5 and NgRx to make the Reactive front end.
- Built from scratch a product website with React and GatsbyJS.
- Convert PHP and Bootstrap website to Svelte, Typescript and Node.js
- Technologies: Bootstrap, Angular Material, NgRx, Angular, Typescript, TailwindCSS, Svelte

01/2018 - 09/2019

REACT DEVELOPER, BCG GAMMA(REMOTE)

- Developed a prototype used to visualize transportation routes using React, Antd, and Deck.gl.
- Built a scheduling tool in the form of a Gantt chart using React and Material-UI.

- Balanced requirements, UX, and deadlines in order to get most of the business value in a limited timeframe.
 - Designed APIs and manipulated big data.
 - Composed scripts—with Python and Node.js—to parse complex data structures.
 - Technologies: Node.js, Recharts, Python, Deck.gl, React

01/2016 - 12/2017

FRONT END DEVELOPER, SUITSUPPLY(US)

- Set up new front-end architecture and worked with the MVC model.
- Building and implementing top-notch user interfaces using JavaScript and the Angular framework.
 - Supported integration of custom live chat for the customer support team.
 - Set up and provision AWS services with AWS Cloud Formation and AWS CDK.
 - Design and develop robust, scalable, extensible web frontend using React JS.
- Technologies: Jenkins, Bower, jQuery UI, jQuery, Git, Subversion (SVN), JavaScript, Compass, Sass, CSS3, HTML, ISML Templates, Demandware

12/2014 - 12/2015

JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER, LIBERTY GLOBAL (UK)

- Developed and improved performance of TV setup box software running on JavaScript engine SpiderMonkey.
 - Developed a TV box weather app.
 - Performing well in a remote setting with frequent communication
 - Layout aesthetics and technical feasibility of UI/UX designs
 - Writing maintainable code that considers accessibility.
 - Technologies: SpiderMonkey, Shell, Linux, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

EDUCATION

04/2009-10/2014

BACHELOR DEGREES OF COMPUTER SCIENCE, TORONTO OF UNIVERSITY

GPA: 4.0

LANGUAGE

• **ENGLISH**, FLUENT

STRENGTH

- COLLABORATION
- HARD WORKING
- BUG FIXING